The new morning we've finally found
やっと見つけた　新しい朝は
Yatto mitsuketa atarashii asa wa
is being hampered by the past.
月日が邪魔をする
Tsukihi ga jama wo suru
What we chased after wasn't the future,
向かう先は　「次」じゃなくて
Mukau saki wa tsugi ja nakute
but the past so full of remorse.
「過」ばかり追いかけた
Sugi bakari oikaketa
The ruthless memories won't stop playing;
鳴り止まない　容赦ない思い出たちは
Nariyamanai yousha nai omoide tachi wa
they won't be forgiving us for a long time.
許してくれそうにもない
Yurushite kuresou nimonai
It's about now that a teardrop
そろそろかな　手探り　疲れた頬を
Sorosoro kana tesaguri tsukareta hoho wo
beings to roll down my fatigued cheeks.
葛藤がこぼれ落ちる
Kattou ga koboreochiru
Will this rain ever stop?
雨は　いつか止むのでしょうか
Ame wa itsuka yamunodeshouka
I've been freezing for a long time.
ずいぶん長い間　冷たい
Zuibun nagai aida tsumetai
Why does the rain continue to fix on me?
雨は　どうして僕を選ぶの
Ame wa doushite boku wo erabuno
I wonder if it could embrace me.
包まれて　いいかな
Tsutsumarete iikana
Today, the rain falls again;
雨は　止むことを知らずに
Ame wa yamu koto wo shirazuni
endlessly it falls knowing no end.
今日も降り続くけれど
Kyou mo furitsuzukukeredo
We nestle close to each other to share the warmth
そっと　差し出した傘の中で
Sotto sashidashita kasa no naka de
under this umbrella, you gently held out to me.
温もりに　寄り添いながら
Nukumori ni yorisoinagara
Huh?
あれ
That's strange, I could have sworn it was this way...
おっかしいな　確か　こっち…
No, was it that way?
いや　あっちか
Are you lost, Fullmetal?
迷子かね　鋼の
うるせぇ
Shut up!
どこぞの無能がバカやってねぇか
We're lost because we came back to make sure that a certain incompetent moron wasn't doing anything dumb!
見に来てやったから
こんな目に遭ってんだよ
No one asked you to do it.
誰も見に来いなんて頼んでないぞ
I'm surprised you can say that!
よく言うぜ
オレとスカーがいなけりゃ
If Scar and I hadn't been there,
てめぇ　絶対に道踏み外してただろ
you definitely would have fallen from the right path!
Quit demanding my gratitude.
恩着せがましく言うな
It's thanks to the Lieutenant that I was able to stop myself.
私があそこで踏みとどまれたのは
中尉のお陰だ
What did you say?!
何ぃ
They're so loud. We're going to be found by the enemy.
やかましいな　敵に見つかるぞ
Scar, I'm going to go ahead and thank you while I still can.
スカー
今のうちに礼を言っておくわ
For convincing the Colonel.
大佐の説得をしてくれたこと
Although it would probably just anger you Ishbalans if you were to be thanked by someone like myself.
あなたたちイシュヴァール人は
私のような者に礼を言われても
腹が立つだけでしょうけど
I think he was able...
あの人　取り戻せたかもしれない
...to return to his old self.
元の自分を
Thank you.
ありがとう
No need to thank me...
感謝の言葉など…
Okay, roger!
はい　はい　了解しました
Understood!
Hey! You can stop firing now!
もう撃たなくていいぞ
砲撃やめ
Cease fire!
A message to the soldiers of the Central Army.
中央軍兵士に告ぐ
We, the Briggs forces, have occupied mission headquarters.
作戦本部は
ブリッグズ軍が占拠した
Damn those traitors...!
We are currently holding thirteen hostages, including Brigadier General Clemin.
クレミン准将を含む
１３名を拘束中　繰り返す
I repeat.
We, the Briggs forces, have occupied mission headquarters.
作戦本部は
我々ブリッグズ軍が占拠した
We demand that the soldiers of the Central Army cease fire immediately.
中央軍兵士は
即刻戦闘を停止せよ
We are currently holding Brigadier General Clemin hostage.
我々はクレミン准将を拘束中である
So the reason why you were going all flashy with the tanks was to mask the noise of the tunnel digging!
戦車で派手に撃ってきたのは
錬金術による穴掘りの音を
かき消すためか
そういうこと
That's right.
What was that?!
なんだって　よく聞こえなかっ…
I couldn't hear!
What?!
何　ほんとか
Is this true?!
What's the matter?
どうした
Mission headquarters has fallen to the Briggs soldiers!
作戦本部が
ブリッグズ兵に落とされました
クレミン准将が拘束されたもよう
Brigadier General Clemin has been taken hostage!
Mission headquarters!
作戦本部　バッカニアはいるか
Is Buccaneer there?
Captain!
大尉
There are a great number of these one-eyed blue humanoid monsters.
人型をした
一つ目玉の青っちろい化け物が
大量発生している
It takes a lot to kill them, and they also eat humans!
こいつら　なかなか
死なないうえに人を食うぞ
No matter what happens, keep all the gates closed!
東西南北　全門
何があっても開けるな
You mustn't let a single one of them out into the city!
一匹たりとも
市街地に出してはならん
Annihilate them within the headquarters grounds!
司令部敷地内で殲滅しろ
Aye, ma'am!
アイ　マム
まったく　何をやっておるのだ
What the hell is Clemin doing?
クレミンのヤツ
From here on out, I'll take charge!
これより私が指揮を執る
This will be the new mission headquarters!
今からここが作戦本部だ
The Führer President's chair...
大総統のイス…
If we overcome this crisis, it'll be mine!
この危機を乗り切れば
この私が
Still more of them?!
まだ  わいて出てくるか
M-Major General, what the hell are these things?!
しょ…少将閣下
こいつら一体なんですか
不死の軍団だそうだ
An immortal army, apparently.
They're soldiers that don't fear death,
人の魂を
でく人形にのせ換えてつくった
死への恐怖を持たない兵士たち
made by affixing human souls onto dolls.
貴様ら一般兵もいつか
You soldiers will someday be turned into those.
これにされることだろうよ
まだ動くのかよ
That thing's still going to move?!
How much does it take to kill it for good?
何回殺せば死ぬんだ…
ならば　もう一発
Then here I go again!
What tenacity...!
なんという執念…
Oh no!
いかん
Major!
Major General Armstrong!
アームストロング少将！ 少佐！
Don't come!
来てはならん
It's after us only!
ヤツの狙いは我らだ
Stay away!
離れていろ
So stubborn.
しぶとい　女将軍　殺す
I'm going to kill the female general!
Pull!
引け
Keep it up!
ふんばれ
Please, you two! Run away while you can!
お二人とも
今のうちに逃げてください
This way! Hurry!
早く　こちらへ
Now, Major!
さあ　少佐殿
Are you asking me to run...?
逃げろというのか…
Are you asking me to run from the battlefield again?!
我が輩にまた
戦場から逃げろというのか
There's no way I could!
そんなまねできるわけがなかろうが
I like that resolve not to run.
いいねぇ　逃げない覚悟
You're quite handsome.
いい男じゃないの
Well, not nearly as handsome as my husband, though.
まっ　うちのだんなの方が
数万倍いい男だけどさ
何者だ
Who are you?
Ah, the female officer.
女性の将校さん
Which means you must be Major General Armstrong.
ってことは　あなたがアームストロング少将ね
あなたの部下のモヒカンさんに
Your subordinate with the mohawk asked me to come help you guys.
こっちに助っ人に行けって頼まれたのよ
That was unnecessary of him...
あいつめ　余計なことを
This is such a drag...
めんどくせぇ
Here he comes, Dear!
あんた　行ったよ
Gotcha!
Who might that gentleman be?
あちらの御仁は
My husband.
うちのだんな
Courage increased by hundred-fold,
muscles increased by thousand-fold!
勇気百倍　筋肉千倍
Ouch...
痛っ
He can still move?!
まだ動くのか
Am I... going to die?
オレ　死ぬの　死ぬ…
Die...?
What does it mean... to die?
死ぬって　なんだ
It's too much of a drag... to think.
考えるの　めんどくせぇ
Even living...
生きてるのも
...is a drag...
めんど…くせぇ…
少佐
Major!
All that's left are the skinny small fries!
残りはガリガリの雑魚どもだけだ
Annihilate them with everything you've got!
全力をもって殲滅しろ
Roger!
Sorry, I need to take a quick break.
すまんが　少し休む
Yes, ma'am!
はっ
あとはお任せください
Please leave the rest to us!
I don't know who you are,
but I very much appreciate your help.
どこのどなたか存ぜぬが
助太刀　感謝する
You're welcome.
どういたしまして
I assume you must be a famous martial artist.
さぞや名のある格闘家とお見受けするが
Me?
私　いえいえ　主婦で錬金術師
No, no, I'm a housewife and an alchemist.
知ってるでしょ
You've heard of the Elric Brothers, right?
エルリック兄弟って
I'm like a relative of theirs.
あれの身内みたいなものよ
So you're Izumi Curtis?
では
あなたがイズミ·カーティス
Yup.
そうよ
Are the Elric Brothers also here?
エルリック兄弟もここに
Yes, they should be.
来てるはずよ
Well then, I guess we should
take care of the rest of the dolls.
さて
残りの人形兵も片づけますか
Can you stand, Sister?
立てますかな　姉上
This is nothing.
なんの　これしき
ちょっと　ちょっと
Hey hey, rest up a bit! You're heavily wounded.
休んでなさいって　そんな傷で…
Us adults can't just lie around while the young ones are fighting.
若い者が戦っておるのに
我ら大人が
寝ているわけにはいきますまい
We have to show the young ones, the ones who will carry this world from now on,
これからこの世を背負っていく若者に
今この世を背負っている大人の…
the way we adults, the ones who currently carry this world, live our lives.
我らの生き様を見せんでなんとする
Then I guess we'll help out too!
そんじゃ私らも手伝いますか
That'll be wonderful!
有り難い
お二人がいれば　百人力ですな
Having you two on our side is equivalent to gaining one hundred men.
Nah... don't expect too much out of us.
いや…
あまり期待しないでちょうだいな
I'm apparently a "human sacrifice" or something,
どうやら私
人柱とかいうやつらしいんで
so I'm going to be getting out of here after I fight for a bit.
ある程度戦ったら
とんずらこかせてもらうわ
Before I get captured by someone really dangerous.
やばいヤツに捕まる前にね
感動の再会なのに　むっつりか
You're being so sullen even though we're in the middle of a heartfelt reunion?
お前　つまらんヤツになったなぁ
You've gotten really boring.
昔はもっと感情が豊かで
You used to be pretty fun, with all those emotions.
おもしろいヤツだったのに
色欲　強欲　怠惰　暴食
Lust, greed, sloth, gluttony, envy, wrath, and pride.
嫉妬　憤怒　傲慢
人には七つの罪があるという
They say that man has seven sins.
確かに過ぎた欲は身を滅ぼすが
Too much greed would certainly destroy one's self,
その一方でそれらの感情すべてが
but on the other hand, all of those emotions are absolutely necessary to understand other humans.
人間を理解するためには
欠かせぬものでもあるはずだ
なぜ切り離した
Why did you let go of them?
ったく　危ないな
Geez, that was dangerous.
人の話 聞け
Listen to what I have to say!
うそ
You're kidding me!
やめてくれよ
Cut it out, man.
オレケンカあんまり強くないんだからさぁ
I'm not too good at fighting.
答えろ
Answer me!
なぜ人造人間をつくり
Why did you create the homunculi, keep them by your side, and have them call you 'Father'?!
そばに置き　父と呼ばせた
フラスコの中にいたころお前は
Back when you were in the flask,
家族というコミュニティーを
you used to even make fun of the community known as a family!
小バカにすらしていたのに
お前本当は　人間のように
Could it be that you actually wanted a family like other humans have?
家族が欲しかったのではないのか
どこだ　まさか
Where did he go?
Don't tell me he's going to hide until the
Nationwide Transmutation Circle activates?
国土錬成陣が発動するまで
引きこもる気か
私は人間になりたいのではない
It's not that I want to become human.
完全な存在になりたいのだ
I want to become a perfect being.
お前の中の賢者の石  もらい受ける
I'm going to be taking...
...the philosopher's stone that's inside of you.
やっと表情が変わったな
Finally, your expression changed.
何をした
What did you do?
お前がしなかったことをしただけさ
Something you didn't do.
分からんだろうな
You probably won't understand.
お前は感情と一緒に
You threw away something important along with your emotions.
大切なものを捨ててしまったんだ
大切なもの
Something important?
簡単に勝てると思うなよ
Don't even think you'll be able to defeat us easily.
オレたちに
なぁ　もう
God dammit!
ダメだな
This won't do.
完全にタイヤがはまってるよ
The tire is completely stuck.
何やってるんだ  チョロひげ
Look what you did, mustache boy!
もたもたしてると日食が始まっちまうぞ
The solar eclipse will begin if we take our time like this!
やかましい
Shut up!
さっさと車を引っ張り上げろ
Hurry up and pull the car out!
やれやれ…
Oh boy...
マルコーさんは離れててください
Doctor Marcoh, please back away.
僕とハインケルさんだけで大丈夫ですよ
Mr. Heinkel and I can handle it.
いや　しかし…
No, but...
大丈夫だって　任せとけ
It'll be fine. Just leave it to us.
ほら　そんじゃあ　いくぞ
Okay, here we go!
いち　にの　さん
One, two, three!
作戦本部へ投降しろ　早く行け
Go surrender to the mission headquarters.
Hurry up and go.
はい
Yes, sir!
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much!
しかし　まあ　人形兵が随分
Well, thanks to the dolls getting rid of so many central soldiers,
中央兵を倒してくれたとみえて
制圧が楽だな
gaining full control of the place is a piece of cake.
このまま一気に正門を取るぞ
We're going to keep up this pace and gain control of the main gate.
アイ　サー
Aye, sir!
オレら　出番ないな…
Looks like there's not much for us to do...
この  とりゃ  なんでだ
You!
Damn you!
Why?!
お前らは我々の命令を聞くように
Weren't you made to listen to our orders?!
つくられてるんじゃなかったのか
あのお方は我々にうそを言っていたのか
Was that man lying to us?!
く…来るな
S-Stay away!
私はこんなところで
I wasn't meant to die here!
死ぬ人間ではないんだ
誰か知らんが  よくやった
I don't know who you are, but good work.
この私の護衛に付け
Be my bodyguard.
そうすれば  特別に…
If you do, I'll specially-
「あのお方」とやらの話
Mind telling us about "that man" whom you speak of?
ちょっと聞かせてもらっていいかな
ひどい有様だな
This is gruesome.
ここで指揮を執られますか
Will you take command from here?
こんな狙撃されやすそうな場所に
I don't understand how someone could sit in a place where they'd make such an easy target for a sniper.
座るヤツの気が知れんわ　行くぞ
Let's go.
はっ
Roger!
姉上
Sister.
どこへ行く通路だ
Where does this passage lead to?
かなり下までいっているようです
Seems like it goes down pretty deep.
人形兵が出てきた穴でしょうか
Could it be the hole which the dolls came out of?
だとしたら　地下に
If so, it could lead underground.
つながっているかもしれんな
はい　はい　了解です
Yes.
Okay, understood.
閣下　バッカニア隊が
Madam!
Buccaneer and his men have captured the main gate.
正門を制圧しました
抵抗少なく　当方の損害軽微
There was little resistance, and they sustained only minor damage.
正門エントランスも制圧
The entrance to the main gate has also been seized.
戦車を収容し
They've stationed the tanks there and are using it as a primary defensive position.
陣地としているとのことです
バッカニア隊は
The Buccaneer squadron shall stay on stand-by.
そのまま待機よろしく
敷地内の人形兵を
Please be sure not to open the gate until every single one of the dolls have been exterminated.
一匹残らず駆逐するまで
門を絶対に開けないようにお願いします
了解した
Roger that.
こちら西門　ブリッグズ
This is the west gate.
We, the white squadron from Briggs, have taken control of the place.
ホワイト隊が制圧しました
北門です  ブラック隊が制圧完了
This is the north gate.
Black squadron, taken control!
ブルー隊　東門制圧
Blue squadron, taken control of the east gate.
イエロー隊  兵器庫を押さえました
Yellow squadron, we've seized their arsenal!
お聞きのとおりです
It's just as you hear, Major General Armstrong!
アームストロング少将閣下
中央司令部の９割を
The Briggs Army has gained control of 90% of Central Headquarters.
ブリッグズ軍が掌握しました
我々の勝利です
Victory is ours.
勝ったぞ
We won!!
大佐　間に合わなかったな…
Looks like the Colonel didn't make it in time.
Hip hip, hooray!
ただいま　諸君
Did you miss me?
私が留守の間に
Seems like you guys started a party while I was away.
随分にぎやかになっているではないか
これより　私自ら指揮を執り
From here on out, I myself will take command and annihilate the traitors.
反逆者を排除する
手の空いている中央兵は手伝いたまえ
I order all unengaged central soldiers to lend me a hand.
キング·ブラッドレイ…
King... Bradley...?!
生きていやがったか
So he was alive.
どこだ　どこから攻めてくる
Where?!
Where will he attack from?!
大総統閣下に敬礼
Salute the Führer President!
Ever since that day passed,
あの日からずっと
Ano hi kara zutto
I promised myself that I'd never cry.
泣かないと決めてきたけど
Nakanaito kimetekitakedo
But even while I hoarded up the pain,
痛みを重ねても
Itami wo kasanetemo
there was something I couldn't forgive myself for.
何かを許せずにいた
Nanika wo yurusezu ni ita
I'll never be able
もう戻れない
Mou modorenai
to return to those days.
いくつもの日々
Ikutsumo no hibi
I'm still powerless.
僕はまだ何もできずに
Boku wa mada nanimo dekizuni
I watch as the shards of memories disappear, one by one;
君のいた記憶の破片
Kimi no ita kioku no kakera
memories of when you were still with me.
またひとつ 消えてゆく
Mata hitotsu kieteyuku
I long to become
今日よりもっと
Kyou yori motto
stronger than I am now,
強くなりたい
Tsuyoku naritai
so that my voice will eventually reach you.
この声がいつか届くように
Kono koe ga itsuka todokuyouni
If the wind happens to stop
歩き続けて
Arukitsuzukete
in the midst of my long journey,
風が止んだら
Kaze ga yandara
I'll look up at the sky in search of you.
君を探して空見上げるよ
Kimi wo sagashite sora miageruyo
Beyond the daybreak, a ray of light breaks free.
夜明けの先に光がさすよ
Yoake no saki ni hikari ga sasuyo
A rainbow spans across the sky.
虹がかかるよ
Niji ga kakaruyo
王の剣がもたらすものは
The king's sword brings about destruction, death,
日本語字幕仕上げ：XIAOBIN
破壊と殺りく　蹂躙と絶望
waste, and despair.
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
圧倒的な力をもって
He devastates all that stands in his way with unmatched power.
立ちふさがるものを撃滅する
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Fullmetal  Alchemist
第５６話　『大総統の帰還』
Episode 56, The Return of the Führer President.
私が帰る場所　それは戦場
His home is the battlefield.